谁买的咖啡  真好
Hey, who went for coffee? Nice.
八百年才回来  没你份了
Oh, you took forever getting back, so you miss out.
-那杯是谁的  -休斯的
- Whose is that?  - Hughes'.
高兴点  我没白磨蹭
Well, you'll be glad I took my time,
我把那贪污案破了
because I solved our embezzlement scam.
拆东墙补西墙的手法
It's a lapping scheme.
拆什么补什么
A lapping scheme?
确实能挪出一大笔钱
It's a way to siphon money.
我来演示
I'll show you.
比方说  我想喝口休斯的咖啡
Let's say I want a sip of Hughes' latte.
-这我懂  -就一口
- Oh, I --  - Just a sip.
真好喝
Wow, that's delicious.
可这就出问题了
But now I have a problem.
你胆大包天
Hughes is gonna toss your butt back into prison
他会一脚把你踢回监狱
for drinking his coffee.
没错  于是
Right, so...
我从你这倒点给他
take a little bit of yours, pour a little bit into here,
你就想踢我了
But now you're gonna kick my butt.
我演示呢嘛
It's a lapping scheme.
就这么一直拆拆补补
I keep going as long as I can.
最后  我喝了一整杯
In the end, I got a full cup of coffee,
-谁都发现不了  -我肯定抓住你
- and no one's the wiser.  - Until I catch you.
不过  干得不错
That's good work, though -- very good work.
我想起来了  琼斯要办香槟早午餐
Hey, June's throwing a champagne brunch. I totally forgot.
我能翘个班吗
Do you mind if I cut out early?
谁那么凶神恶煞
What kind of monster would I be
敢拦着尼尔·卡夫瑞出席早午餐
to keep Neal Caffrey from a champagne brunch?
各位回见
See you, guys.
收到你信息
Got your message.
想你也该打来了
I was wondering when you were gonna call.
下水聊呗
Hop in. We'll chat.
我可没带泳裤
Forgot my suit.
以前还不是裸泳
That's never stopped you before.
行了  知道你戴了脚链
Relax, I know you're wearing the anklet.
可你身上搞不好还有窃听器
What I don't know is if you're wired.
下水
Get in.
八音盒在哪  艾莱士
Where's the music box, Alex?
不先聊聊吗
No small talk?
说吧  之前你说在曼哈顿
Come on. Your note said it's in Manhattan.
我怕你甩开我  独
I want to make sure you're not gonna go
自去偷啊
and get it without me.
都说了  我们一起行动
I told you. We'll get it together.
东西在意大利领事馆
It's in the Italian consulate.
我查到  它落在总领事手里
I traced it to the Consul General.
他去年拿到的
He tucked the box
放在领事馆  他私人保险箱里
into his private safe in the consulate last year.
他下个月就来把它拿走
He's flying in next month to pick it up.
领事的东西可不好偷啊
A consulate's a hard target.
馆里下周要开派对
They're having a party next week.
有机会混进去
It's our chance to get inside.
我就是个派对动物
I'm always up for a party.
他发现东西丢了  会怎样
What happens when he notices it's gone?
那盒子本来就是德国佬从俄国偷来的
Well, the Nazis stole the box from the Russians.
就不该落在这领事手里
He wasn't supposed to have it in the first place,
东西丢了  他只能哑巴吃黄连
so he won't talk when we steal it from him.
有件事我不懂
I got a question.
我没带泳裤  才裸泳
I know why I'm naked.
你干嘛也裸着
Why are you?
要偷领事的东西吗
A consulate?
牛  要成国际大案了
Oh, great, an international incident.
我可不想在地下黑屋里终老
Look, I don't want to end my days in some underground prison,
还跟小强拜把子
adopting cockroaches as pets.
又不是北朝鲜
We're not talking about North Korea.
意大利佬而已  蚊子
It's the Italians, Moz.
那也不好住啊  看伽利略惨的
They do prison just fine. Ask Galileo.
能不带艾莱士吗
Can we do it without Alex?
不行  她不告诉我是哪个保险箱
No. She won't tell me which safe it's in.
-小妞一直这么贼  -那可不
- She was always a smart girl.  - Yeah.
反正也不能行动
All of this is moot, anyhow.
你家那位最近可不会让你卸脚链
The suit isn't gonna let you out of your anklet anytime soon.
不找彼得
Not Peter.
-那找谁  -福勒
- Then who?  - Fowler.
他要想通过我拿到八音盒
If he wants me to get him the music box,
就得帮我卸脚链
he has to cut my anklet.
他以前也不是没动过
He's manipulated it before.
行  就算卸了脚链
Okay. Let's say he goes for it.
你替他弄到了八音盒
Let's say you get him the box.
-接着怎么办  -什么怎么办
- Then what?  - What do you mean?
盒子交给福勒
You give Fowler the music box,
凯特飞扑入怀
and Kate comes running into your arms.
你们就买个房安定下来
You settle down, buy a fixer-upper,
结婚生子了吗
and then join the P.T.A?
是啊
Yeah.
尼尔  我们这种人  少有大团圆结局
Neal, happily ever after isn't for guys like us.
这次肯定团圆  一定
It is this time. It is.
请转221分机  找福勒探员
Agent Fowler, Extension 221.
请稍等
One moment.
福勒探员办公室
Agent Fowler's office.
转告他  我有那八音盒的消息
Tell him I've got information on the music box he requested.
-你是哪位  -他心里有数
- Who is this?  - He knows.
明天午夜见面
He can meet me at midnight, tomorrow.
在哪见面
Where?
以后告诉他
He'll know that, too.
太神秘了是不
Too cryptic?
准备在哪见面
Where you gonna meet him?
这就找
I'll find a place.
有监控任务吗
Hey, you got a stakeout?
有  辛辣火腿
Yep. Deviled ham.
你是准备辣死他
Well, you're either gonna torture Neal with it
还是准备自残
or you're going alone.
走着瞧
We'll see.
怎么了
What's going on?
看
Look.
尼尔的监控数据  他又要干嘛
Neal's tracking data. What's he up to now?
还没行动
Nothing, yet.
他昨晚在肯氏街和拉氏街附近
He spent 45 minutes on the corner of
游荡了45分钟
Kenmare and Lafayette last night.
他可以在两英里内自由活动吧
Well, honey, he can walk freely for a two-mile radius, right?
对  但他的走法很可疑  看
Yeah, but it's the way he was walking. Look.
他在这停车场的每个角落
He stands at every corner around this parking garage
各停了两分钟
for exactly two minutes.
停车场往四面的通路
He walks each street leading away from this point
他都来回走过
and then back again.
你觉得他在干嘛
What do you think he was doing?
踩盘子
I think he was casing the area --
观察人流量  确定摄像头方位
how many people are around, where there were cameras,
这是在安排逃跑路线
looking for an escape route in case he needs one.
他要干什么
What is he planning?
多半是要偷那八音盒
I think he's gonna steal the music box.
从街角偷吗
On a street corner?
我还在想
Working theory.
那你好好干
Well, have fun on your stakeout.
爱你
I love you.
福勒
Fowler.
噢  还带了伙计来
Oh, you brought a friend.
没窃听器啦
I'm not wired.
我多疑  你懂的
You'll forgive me if I don't take your word for it.
没手脚
He's clean.
有何贵干
This better be good.
那八音盒  我就快拿到了
I'm close to the music box.
和我有关系吗
That supposed to mean something to me?
你特意从华盛顿赶回来  没关系才怪
Well, you flew in from D.C., so I think it does.
路子下周就走不通了
My window to get the box closes in the next week.
卸了脚链  才能成事
I need my tracking anklet off now to make it happen.
卡夫瑞  你不是要拖我下水吧
You're not suggesting something illegal, are you, Caffrey?
当然不是
Of course not,
你在局里位高权重  我怎么敢
especially to an upstanding federal agent such as yourself.
别见好不收
You're pushing it.
我待会再收
I'm gonna push it some more.
你拿了盒子  就再别管我和凯特
I give you the box, Kate and I never hear from you again.
这是我的条件
That's my price.
卡夫瑞  爱怎么闹随你
You know, I don't give a damn what you do, Caffrey.
可别牵扯上我
Just don't make it my problem.
尼尔啊尼尔  你到底背着我搞什么鬼
Neal, what the hell are you doing?
第一季第14集（季终）
猫鼠游戏 [妙警贼探]
这可是意大利领事馆
This is the Italian consulate.
不是什么银行博物馆
It's not a bank or a museum.
是外国佬的地盘
It's a little piece of a foreign country.
要能有辆坦克  或者空军助阵
If we had a tank, maybe, or an air force.
空军就别想了
We don't have an air force,
靠公民身份  我们能穿过第一道安保门
but the party will get us past the first wall of security
进到主宴会厅
and into the main ballroom.
至于内部密室
There's only one way into the inner sanctum.
只能从这道门进去
It's through this security door.
最难就是这道门
This door is our biggest obstacle.
对  没键盘锁  没指纹锁  没锁孔
Uh, yeah -- there's no keypads, no biometrics, no lock.
除非保安室的警卫放行
The only way is to get buzzed through by a guard
不然死活进不去
stationed in the security room.
-这事我解决  -赞
- Let me worry about that.  - Grand.
穿过门  是一条长廊
Once I'm through, there's a long stretch of hallway
有闭路电视监控
monitored by a closed-circuit camera.
穿过长廊
When I make it down the hallway,
就能进保险库
I can get into the vault room.
到底是哪个保险箱
Which safe is it, exactly?
到时候告诉你
I'll let you know.
不了解清楚  我怎么开锁
And when I find the safe, all I have to do is crack it.
高安全保险箱  还防火
It's high-security and torch-resistant.
要凿穿防火板
Uh, you'll need heavy metal
得带点厉害家伙
to get through the fire-resistant plate.
那都是细节  一个一个来
Details. One thing at a time, Moz.
先说怎么入场
Let's start with party invites.
我准备搭个单身男客
I'm looking for a man without a plus-one.
这位似乎不错  伊格内修斯·巴登
I'm leaning towards this gentleman, Ignatius Barden.
-干嘛选他  -他是个公爵
- Why him?  - He's a duke.
低调点行吗
Wouldn't someone a little less conspicuous do?
我一直都想和公爵跳舞啊
I always wanted to dance with a duke.
得  你简历交了吗
All right. You submit your resume yet?
今天早上送到餐饮公司了
The catering company received it this morning.
您可是顶级蛋糕屋业主[参见第七集]
As the proprietor of the greatest cake bakery,
开个华丽的介绍信给我吧
I fully expect a glowing reference.
-没问题  -你呢
- Of course.  - What's your in?
我有个玩意
I'm planning to make
准备慷慨赠予意大利人
a very generous donation to the people of Italy.
尼尔  有客来了
Neal, uh, company is on the way.
谢谢你
Thank you.
看看呐  看看
Oh, look at this --
几个惯犯全到齐了
All the usual suspects in one place.
我倒是省事儿了  小朋友们忙什么呐
Makes my job much easier. What are you kids up to?
我们正好要走了
We were just leaving.
我想也是
Ah, I bet you were.
我知道你去见过福勒
I know you met with Fowler.
现在艾莱士和你那小伙计都来了
And now Alex and your little buddy are here.
你倒是把偷八音盒的人手都找齐了
You've got your whole crew to steal the box.
要反驳吗
Tell me I'm wrong.
你误会了
You're wrong?
我真搞不懂你
I don't understand you.
我这么宠你  想让你过更幸福的生活
I gave you a shot at a better life.
我想要的不是那种生活
It's not the life I want.
好吧  我们都有弱点
Okay. Well, we all have our weakness.
凯特是你的弱点
Kate's yours.
别做傻事  尼尔
Do the right thing, Neal.
如果你以为凯特和你同一战线
You're fooling yourself
那你是在自欺欺人
if you think Kate's on your side.
监视卡夫瑞家时拍下的照片
Surveillance photos from Caffrey's place.
博尔克去找他了
Oh, Burke showed up?
是啊  他看上去不太开心
Yeah. He didn't look happy.
是我们见卡夫瑞那晚脚链的追踪数据
He pulled Caffrey's tracking data the night we met with him.
他还私下调查了
He also slipped in a request
我在纽约的行动
asking what I'm up to in New York.
你可真聪明啊  博尔克探员
Aren't you clever, agent Burke?
在监视他的手下吗
You keeping an eye on his people?
琼斯和克鲁兹  24小时监视
Jones and Cruz, 'round the clock.
有进展了  不过我们可能有点麻烦
Mentor is moving forward, but we might have a problem.
博尔克探员试图干涉
Agent Burke might try to interfere.
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
是  我能搞定博尔克
Yeah, I can -- I can take Burke out of play,
只要你别忘了我们的交易
as long as you remember our deal --
我给你八音盒  一切就结束了
I get the box, and this is over.
约会很顺利呀
Your date went well?
一个公爵带你去的地方
You'd be amazed the kinds of places
你绝对意想不到
a duke gets you access to.
我以为你只是利用他当宴会舞伴呢
And I thought you were just using him for a plus-one.
行动过程中找点乐子也没关系啊
No harm in having a little fun while I'm at it.
你给那帮意大利人的礼物吗
Your gift to the italians?
是凡切利的作品  火神像
It's Fancelli's study, "Statua di Vulcano."
很漂亮
This is beautiful.
和真品一样
Looks like the real thing.
别让他蒙蔽你的双眼
Don't let it fool you.
不会的
I won't.
有些事我们一直在逃避
There's something we've been avoiding.
我觉得是时候谈谈了
I think it's time to talk about it.
好
All right.
我知道你我的关系很复杂
Look, I know you and I have a complicated relationship --
我是说这个
I mean this.
如果你不能摘下脚链
If you can't get it off,
那所有计划都是浮云  而我们在做的这些
then none of this will matter, and everything we're doing --
我会有办法
It'll happen, all right?
要喝杯红酒吗
Can I get you a glass of wine?
好
Okay.
你还记得上次吗
You remember the last time
我们也是离八音盒咫尺之遥
we were this close to getting the box?
在哥本哈根  偷溜进阿美琳堡王宫
Copenhagen, sneaking into the Amalienborg Palace,
和王室谈天说地
hanging out with the royal family.
这是从警卫室跳下来时弄伤留下的疤
I have a scar from the jump off the gatehouse.
痊愈得不错
It healed nicely.
你都没去医院看我
You didn't visit me in the hospital.
你也没去监狱看我
You didn't visit me in prison.
你在哥本哈根把那桥给烧了
You burned that bridge in Copenhagen.
-你背叛了我  -我们都背叛了对方
- You cut me out, a...  - We cut each other out.
-我们  -就是这种人
- That's...  - Who we are.
这次可不是闹着玩的
It's not a game this time.
拜托  我知道你会拿走八音盒
Come on. I know you're gonna take the box.
也知道是为了凯特
I know this is about Kate.
艾莱士  看
Alex, look.
少忽悠我  咱俩还来这套就没身价儿了
Don't lie to me, Neal. It's humiliating for both of us.
这个灯从没有灭过
This light's never been off before.
福勒干的吗
Fowler came through?
看来万事俱备了
I think we're in play.
我觉得这个鱼子酱
I think this caviar will go lovely
配肥鹅肝和香槟酒一定非常美味
with the foie gras and the champagne.
我还想给您介绍一下餐桌摆设
Oh, and I want to try and show you the table settings.
我找伊丽莎白·博尔克
I'm looking for Elizabeth Burke.
我就是
I'm Elizabeth.
博尔克夫人  我们怀疑
Miss Burke, we got a tip
你在进行非法交易
that you have contraband on the premises.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
请等我一下
Just give me a second.
我相信你应该清楚  对于进口
I'm sure you're aware there are restrictions
某些外国食物及酒精有宪法规定
on the import of certain foreign foods and spirits.
我们要进行全面搜查
We'll need to search everything.
等等  你这是干什么
Whoa, whoa, wait a minute. What are you doing?
你得有个搜查令吧
You need a search warrant for that.
你是谁
Who are you?
联邦探员  女士
FBI, ma'am.
你是调查局的人
You're with the bureau?
你知道我老公是谁吗
Do you know who my husband is?
当然
I do.
你觉得你的电话被监听了
You think your phone's being tapped?
监听别人电话的事儿我可干多了
I've been on the other side enough
一听那咔嚓声就知道了
to recognize those clicks.
这可不妙啊  劳伦呢
That's not good. Lauren?
一样  现在福勒又回来了
Same. And now Fowler's back.
你觉得和他有关系吗
You think there's a connection?
-小伊  怎么了  -亲爱的  我需要你
- Hey, EL, what's up?  - Honey, I-I need you.
怎么了
What's the matter?
他们要把我办公室弄散架了
They're -- they're tearing apart my office.
-谁  -联邦探员
- Who? - The FBI.
拜托  别碰那个
Please, please don't touch that.
-小伊  她是说联邦探员吗  -是
- El, did...She say FBI?  - Yeah.
-请说指令  -路况
- Please say a command. - Traffic.
路况
Traffic.
看来公园大街和34号街有交通事故
Looks like there's an accident on park and 34th.
亲爱的
Honey.
怎么回事  这儿谁负责啊
Hey, what's going -- hey, who's in charge here?
请和我的嫌犯保持距离  博尔克
Stay away from my suspect, Burke.
嫌犯
Your suspect?
你玩儿过了吧  福勒
You're way out of bounds here, Fowler.
福勒  等等
Fowler? Wait.
-就是你在我家装的窃听器吗  -亲爱的
- You're the man who violated our home?  - All right, honey.
我来和他谈  好吗
Let me talk to him, all right?
你害我老公差点丢了工作
You almost ruined my husband's career.
最好劝她冷静点  博尔克
You better calm your wife down here, Burke.
不用你说
I'll calm her down.
我冷静什么啊我
I will not calm down.
好吧  你这是袭警
All right, that is assaulting an agent.
你开玩笑呢啊
Are you kidding me?
-简直荒谬至极  -你被捕了
- This is absolutely ridiculous! - You're under arrest.
老天  福勒  你开玩笑呢吧
Jesus, Fowler, you have got to be kidding me!
你被停职了  博尔克探员
You just got yourself a suspension, agent Burke.
琼斯  对吧  没收他的枪和警徽
Jones, right? Take his gun and badge.
让您自己的手下动手  长官
You got your own guys for that...Sir.
没收他的枪和警徽
Take his gun and badge.
没关系  琼斯
It's all right, Jones.
停职也值了
It was worth it.
亲爱的  别这样  小伊
Honey, come on. El. El.
我们谈谈好吗
Can we just -- let's talk about this.
还有什么好谈的
Is there really anything to talk about?
我被保释  你连工作都没了
I mean, I'm out on bail and you're out of a job.
不是  只是停职两周罢了
No, it's just a two-week suspension.
-我被逮捕了  -我知道
- Babe, I was arrested...  - I know.
还在我客户面前被戴上手铐
...and handcuffed in front of my clients.
2周之内我有生意做就算幸运了
I'll be lucky if I have a business in two weeks.
现在呢  我还得打电话去解释
You -- and now I have to call and explain
为什么2000块的鱼子酱
why $2,000 worth of caviar
变成美国政府的财产了
is the property of the U.S. government.
好了好了  乖
All right, all right, all right, all right.
过来  来
Come here. Come here. Come here.
老天
God.
乖  没事
Come here. Come here.
我爱你  小伊
I love you, EL.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
别道歉
Oh, don't be sorry.
快给我搞定他
Just -- just get him.
有话就说
What is it?
我刚听说
I just heard --
别说了
Don't.
我不知道会这样  彼得
I didn't know this would happen, Peter.
我不知道他会去找你麻烦
I didn't know he'd go after you.
我才不想听你道歉
I don't want your apology.
话说前头  这两周恐怕你得
For the record, you just bought yourself
乖乖在家呆着了
two weeks' house arrest.
琼斯告诉我了
Jones told me.
你要是敢离开你家半步  你就完了
You try leaving the apartment, you're done for.
这下你能在家好好研究你那小计划了
So good luck planning your little caper.
等会  我跟你没完呢
Hold on. I'm not done with you.
关于那个软禁在家的问题
About that house-arrest thing...
我没想到他会来找伊丽莎白的麻烦
I never thought he'd come after Elizabeth.
你要相信我
You have to believe me.
我才不在乎你想什么呢
I don't care what you thought.
我这么多年的工作就要毁你俩手上了
You're helping him destroy everything I've worked for,
还有我妻子的工作
everything my wife has worked for.
他让你停职  这样你就不能阻止我了
He took you out so you couldn't stop me.
我知道  我还自己送上门儿
I know, and I walked right into it.
像你说的  我们都有弱点
Well, like you said, we all have our weaknesses.
他抓了凯特  还发现了你的弱点
He's got mine. He found yours.
这件事结束后  我们就让他永远倒台
When this is over, we take him down...for good.
看这个
Look at this.
尼尔  灯灭了
Neal, your light is off.
是啊  可据琼斯所说
Yeah, but according to Jones,
监测站显示我在自己家里
the monitoring station says I'm at home.
为什么信号停止传输了
Why isn't it transmitting?
福勒
Fowler.
他关闭信号传输  好方便你去偷八音盒
He shut you down so you could steal the box.
他怎么做到的
How'd he do that?
-我不知道  -我都想佩服他了
- I don't know.  - I'm almost impressed.
你不逮捕我吗
You're not gonna arrest me?
怎么捕  我又没警徽
I can't. I don't have a badge.
好吧
All right.
就算你偷天换日的计划能成功
Let's say you pull off this heist.
你真觉得他会放过你和凯特吗
You really think he's gonna let you and Kate go?
我要知道她是不是
I need to know if she's...
为了伊丽莎白你也会这么做
You'd do the same for Elizabeth.
今天我认栽  不和你争
After today, I'm not gonna argue that.
我要给他点颜色瞧瞧
I'm gonna beat him.
你打算怎么做
What are you gonna do?
福勒敢扣我的徽章  我就以牙还牙
Fowler took my badge. I'm gonna take his.
以他企图协助你犯案的名义
He's aiding you in illegal activity.
我只是在做我的分内事
I'm just doing my part.
他盯着你和你同事的一举一动
He'll be watching you and everyone you work with.
我知道
I know.
我要找个帮手  有联调局权限
I'll need help from somebody with FBI access
还不会被福勒缠上
who Fowler can't link to me,
我必须可以信任
somebody I can trust.
你看上谁了吗
You got someone in mind?
你能来太好了
Thanks for coming.
这还用说吗  头儿
You knew I would, boss.
别再那样叫我了
You don't have to call me that anymore.
-你家那位怎么样  -克里斯蒂吗
- How's, uh... - Christy?
-是啊  -她很好
- Yeah. - Oh, she's good.
那就好
Good, good, good. Good.
在华盛顿过得习惯吗
You guys like D.C.?
就那样  物是地非而已
Mm, different city, same paperwork.
我真该留在这里
I should have stuck around.
和卡夫瑞共事还挺有趣
Things are probably more interesting with Caffrey.
有点过了头
Too interesting.
你为了他才找我来的吧
Uh-huh. He the reason I'm here?
戴安  我这次要你帮的忙
Diana, what I'm about to ask you to do
可非比寻常
is a lot more than paperwork.
我要拜托你查一个职责办的探员
I need you to look into an OPR agent --
加里特·福勒
Agent Garrett Fowler.
他篡改了尼尔脚链的数据
Somehow, he's manipulating Neal's anklet.
为什么
Why?
尼尔能弄到他想要的东西
Neal has access to something he wants.
看来他一点也没变
Huh. Sounds like he hasn't changed.
变了就不是尼尔了
No, same old Neal.
他不会还戴着那顶帽子吧
He still wearing the hat?
别提了
Oh, please.
进展如何
How did it go?
一切顺利
Good.
领事馆接受你的礼物了吗
The consulate accepted your gift?
我和领事馆代表托马西先生谈妥了
I spoke to Mr. Tomassi, the consulate manager.
凡切利的火神像已在密室里沉思了
Fancelli's Study of Vulcan is now in the inner sanctum.
保安系统如何
How's the security?
跟我们的预期无二
Like we expected.
第一道门得用磁卡打开
The outer door opens with a key card.
是我  开门
Buzz us through.
第二道门呢  有法子过去吗
Mm, what about the inner door? Can we get through?
我自有办法
I'll figure out a way.
-他请你去宴会了吗  -请了
- He invited you to the party? - He did.
艾莱士呢
Alex?
她可是公爵的女伴  你呢
She's the duke's plus-one. You?
你面前是个管家助理  菜鸟级别的
You're looking at the new assistant server...trainee.
只要我想  不出3个月就会满嘴蛀牙
If I play my cards right, I get dental in three months.
抱歉啦  我们开工吧
All right. Then we're ready.
得把这玩意拿掉  劳驾了
Let's cut it off. You want to do the honors?
不如我先来个祝酒词
I feel like I should make a toast or something.
逃避即自由  就算是刚出虎口又入狼窝地
We feel free when we escape, even if it be
飞蛾扑火  埃里克·霍夫名言
but from the frying pan into the fire -- Eric Hoffer.
果然没警报
No sirens.
没的回头啦
Into the fire.
加里特·福勒的资料都在这了
This is everything I could find on Garrett Fowler.
不是很多
Not much there --
我提出要彻查他的档案
I've put in a request to go after his files.
还在等法官批准
I'm just waiting on the judge.
这些足够了  他可是抢劫犯的帮凶
We don't need much. He's aiding a premeditated robbery.
-脚链就是铁证  -你确定是他吗
- The anklet is the key. - And you're sure it's him?
福勒之前也篡改过尼尔的记录
Fowler's doctored Caffrey's information in the past,
现在又故技重施
and he's doing it now.
他到底是怎么办到的
I need to know how.
由司法官监控脚链的情况
Well, marshals monitor the anklet.
是司法部收回了管理权
Department of Justice supersedes their authority.
而福勒可能越权钻了空子
Fowler could override them and get access.
或是远程操控数据
Or he's altering the data remotely.
通过公共网络可不行
Mm-hmm. You can't do that from just any internet connection.
得有一条保密通路
He'd need a secure line.
这样足不出职责办就能搞定
He's doing it from OPR offices.
我得去他们纽约的办事处转转
They have one in New York. That's where I need to go.
外人可进不去  除非你有联调
Well, nobody gets into that building without federal cl--
联调许可和预约
Federal clearance and an appointment.
我进不去  连门都摸不到
They wouldn't let me within a hundred yards.
我能进去
But they'd let me.
一旦被福勒发现  你在调查局可混不下去了
Fowler finds out, and it's career suicide.
我这不是来帮你的吗
I came here to help you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
他到底要这音乐盒做什么
This music box -- what happens if he gets it?
不知道  保证他拿不到就成
I don't know...But we need to make sure he doesn't.
托马西阁下
Signore Tomassi?
丹弗瑞先生
Ah. Mr. Danvary.
叫我乔治就好
Please, call me George.
乔治
George,
再次对您无与伦比的捐赠表示感谢
thank you again for your remarkable donation.
我知道凡切利的作品
Oh, well, I know how important
对意大利雕塑界意义重大
Fancelli's work is to Italian sculpture.
我怎么忍心把它
I couldn't just let it sit around
搁我家阁楼上积灰呢
in my family's attic, collecting dust.
您所言极是
No, of course not.
总领事已经吩咐把作品
The consul general has requested the piece be placed
放在他办公室内的最佳位置
in perfect view of his office.
凡切利是他最欣赏的艺术家
Fancelli is his favorite artist.
是吗  真没想到
Really? I had no idea.
我能亲眼看看吗
Could I see it?
很抱歉  恕难让您如愿
I'm sorry. I'm afraid that won't be possible.
不过请放心  它非常安全
But rest assured it's very safe.
-好吧  -祝您今晚过得愉快
- Okay. - Please enjoy your evening.
伏特加酒加冰  谢谢
Ketel One on the rocks, please.
我去去就来
I'll be right back.
真对不起  先生
Oh, I'm so sorry, sir.
抱歉  请原谅[意大利语]
Excuse me. Mi scusi.
漂亮
Nice lift.
谢谢  这下能进第一道门
Thanks. This will get you through the first door.
你今天很帅气
You clean up nice.
你也不赖
Not so bad yourself.
好运  卡夫瑞
Good luck, Caffrey.
艾莱士
Alex.
到底在哪个保险柜
Which safe is it?
三层防盗锁  外壳坚不可摧
Triple-walled, case-hardened steel.
麦金泽1943年制造
1943 Mckinzie.
不会让我们轻易得手吧
Couldn't make this easy for us, could they?
太容易就不好玩了
Where's the fun in that?
里头见
I'll see you on the inside.
各位  各位[意大利语]
Excuse me! Scusi! Pardon!
我愿敬我们亲切的主人一杯
I'd like to make a toast to our gracious hosts...
还有在场的各位  今夜如此与众不同
...And to all of you, because this is a very special night --
尤其是对我来说
Well, it's special to me, anyway.
你们可能不知道我是谁
You probably have no idea who I am,
请允许我自我介绍
so I'm going to tell you.
我是个举世闻名的雅贼
I'm an internationally renowned art thief.
今晚  我要偷走你的一件东西
And tonight, I'm here to rob you.
干杯
Cheers!
女士们先生们  这位宾客可能
Signore, signore, it seems one of our gueststs
有些微醺
has had too much to drink.
还请各位海涵  继续享受晚宴
Please continue to enjoy your evening.
要香槟吗  女士
Champagne, madame?
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you.
他很有把握哦
He made that look easy.
该我们上了
Our turn.
放我们过去
Buzz us through.
你究竟有何目的
Tell me why you're really here.
我说了  我来偷东西
Well, I told you. I'm here to rob you.
我明白了
I see.
这下我更不告诉你了
Well, now I'm definitely not gonna tell you.
对讲机给我
Give me your walkie.
把他关在这  跟我走
Lock him in here. Come with me.
把所有人转移到中庭  封锁出口
Move everyone into the atrium. No one leaves here.
我们要一一盘查
We check everyone.
是  先生
Yes, sir.
快点儿  蚊子
Come on, Moz.
尼尔
Neal.
你在哪
Where are you?
我到玻璃门这边了
The other side of the glass.
区域一疏散完毕
Unit one clear.
区域二  东面楼梯
Unit two, east stairwell.
快
Go.
可惜了我的杰作
Some of my best work.
尼尔  动作快
Neal, hurry up.
我的胳膊被托酒盘折磨得好苦
My arm's killing me from holding that drink tray.
解除警报
Shut off the alarm.
快去密室
The security room -- go.
你真够不慌不忙
Take your time, why don't you?
是生疏了吗
You're losing your touch.
我来了
Let me in.
一切顺利吗
Everything okay?
我们成功了  尼尔
We did it, Neal.
先从这儿出去再说
We're not out of here yet.
下面有人
There's somebody down there.
别卿卿我我了  他们来了
That's very touching, guys, but they're coming!
艾莱士
Alex.
Alex!
还愣着干吗  他们下来了
Hurry up! They're coming!
快过来  蚊子
Come on, mozzie.
从另一边过去
Go around.
某个喜着华服的同学被全境通告了啊
There's an APB out for a man of interest in a slick suit.
还从领事馆骑墙而下
Apparently he rappelled down the wall of a consulate.
不要紧的
It'll be fine.
这东西本就来路不明
They're not gonna prosecute for the theft of an item
他们做贼心虚  不会告我的
they weren't supposed to have in the first place.
这东西好像不在你手上
An item you don't seem to have.
就当是艾莱士背叛了我们
Well, let's just say Alex had other plans.
-我早该预料到  -知道她会去哪吗
- Should have seen it coming. - Any idea where she went?
她是中途变卦的
She didn't stick to the plan.
没跟我们一起离开领事馆
She got out of the consulate a different way.
如果她想跑  没人能抓到她
If Alex wants to disappear, she does.
没有八音盒  福勒就得逞了
Without that box, Fowler's side wins.
告诉我
I need to know.
我们呢  算是自己人吗
What about us? Are we on the same side here?
你说过我有权自己决定
You said I earned the right to make my own choices.
你也变卦了吗
You changing your mind?
福勒仍在虎视眈眈
Fowler's still out there.
这事儿还没完呢
This isn't over yet.
你这是什么意思
What do you mean by that?
我自有办法对付他
I have something in play.
你再这样不消停
You're going to burn a hole right through my floor
我家地板迟早被你走出个洞来
if you keep that up.
不管是什么让你心烦意乱
Whatever's bothering you,
相信我  船到桥头自然直
Believe me, it's gonna work out.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
谢谢你为我做的一切
Thank you... For everything.
我不相信再见
Oh, you know I don't believe in goodbye.
尼尔  在芸芸众生中  你是万里挑一
Neal, you are one in a million.
千万别忘了
And don't you forget it.
我还以为此生再不能相见呢
Didn't know if I'd ever see you again.
真巧  我也一样
Funny. I was thinking the same thing.
但还是给你  趁我没改变主意
But here... Before I change my mind.
你不知道  这对我意义重大
You don't know what this means to me.
我想我懂
I think I do.
但愿凯特如你所想
I hope Kate's still the same girl
仍和以前一样
you think she is.
最近我也深有体会
I'm getting that a lot lately.
既然你不相信她  又为何要回来
If you don't trust her, why'd you bring this back?
因为我不想就这么告别
Because I don't want this to be goodbye...
万一我错了呢
in case she's not.
再加上  我突然觉得
And plus, I figured I don't need
我不想招惹这么大的麻烦
all the heat this is gonna bring.
我可不想对付你家那位
I don't need the same guy who's been after you
一直和你纠缠不清的家伙
coming after me.
你的决定总是很明智
You always made smart decisions.
你真该学学我
You should try it sometime.
福勒刚离开办公室喝咖啡去了
Fowler just left for his coffee break.
我这就进去
I'm about to enter his office.
查他的笔记本  小心点
Aim for his laptop, Diana, and be careful.
不消他一口玛奇朵的功夫我就能完事
I'll be out before he can take his first sip of macchiato.
东西呢
That it?
先给我保证
I want assurances.
指导会是为我而开
Mentor was created for me?
凯特和我商量好了  你们一人一个新身份
Kate and I made a deal. You both get new identities.
而八音盒归我们
We get the box.
你们从此销声匿迹
You disappear...
而这次是合法的
...legally.
给
Here you go.
为什么这么执着于这个八音盒
What's so special about that box?
这就不归我管了
That's above my pay grade.
凯特在等你呢
Kate's waiting for you.
时间地点在文件夹里
Time and place are in that folder.
好好过日子啊  卡夫瑞
Have a nice life, Caffrey.
一定
Yeah.
有事吗
Can I help you?
我是情报部的
Hey. I'm from I.T.
福勒探员申请另要一份安全协议
Agent Fowler requested another security protocol,
他坚持安排在下午茶时间
insisted we schedule during his coffee break.
你也知道他的脾气
You know how he gets.
对
Yeah.
快啊
Hurry, hurry, come on.
文件下载完毕
我是福勒
Fowler.
我们有麻烦了
Hey, we got a problem.
有人动了你的电脑
There was somebody on your computer here.
她自称是情报部的
She said she was from I.T.
什么  她动了什么
What? Did she get anything?
她下载了所有指导文件
She downloaded the whole mentor file.
看来她整个硬盘都扫荡了一遍
It looks like she got the whole hard drive.
见鬼
Damn it.
首都授权的消失行动
A washington-approved disappearing act.
技术层面上而言  我是职责办的人
Well, technically, I work for OPR.
技术层面上而言  只是理论上而已
Well, technically. That's just on paper.
有这个新身份作掩护
With this new identity,
你和凯特可以随心所欲了
You can go anywhere, with Kate.
而且还完全合法
And it's legal.
太有才了
It's genius.
没人能找到你们
No one will be able to find you --
不论是政府机关还是旧敌故友
Governments, old enemies, old friends.
还记得那句中国古语吗
Remember that old chinese curse?
愿你生活的时代妙趣横生
May you live in interesting times.
这一点自然毋庸置疑
These certainly are interesting times.
还记得后半句吗
Remember the second half of that curse?
愿你心中所想能美梦成真
May you find what you're looking for.
和你家那位也说再见了吗
Gonna say goodbye to the suit?
给我寄明信片
Send me a postcard.
1号快拨键
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth.
尼尔  这算什么
Neal? What is this?
我有个朋友在钱宁博物馆
I got a friend at the Channing Museum.
今天会给你电话  他欠我个人情
He's gonna call you today. He owes me a favor.
真的吗  为什么
Really? Why?
雇博尔克首映项目公司
To hire Burke Premiere Events
主办他们的年度大师作品回顾展
to do their annual masters retrospective.
这种机会绝无仅有
That's -- that's -- that's impossible to get.
那你就是那个仅有了
Well, you just got it.
你为何这么做
Why are you doing this?
只是为了弥补我的过失
Just trying to fix what I broke.
我想问你些事
There's something I wanted to ask you.
说吧
Yeah?
你和彼得之间...
You and Peter --
你怎么知道他是命中注定的那个人
How'd you know?
这样啊
Well...
我觉得爱一个人
I think there's a difference
理想和现实
between loving the idea of someone...
两者之间难免有所差别
and actually loving who they really are.
听着  我得挂了  谢谢你
Listen, I got to go. Thanks for everything.
好  我们回头再聊
Okay. Well, um, I'll -- I'll talk to you later.
再见  伊丽莎白
Goodbye, Elizabeth.
我正往车库走
I'm headed to the garage.
我查到了指导会的内幕  你肯定大吃一惊
I've got everything on mentor. You're not gonna believe it.
尼尔也牵涉其中吗
Is Neal involved?
岂止是牵涉  另有一份文件被加了密
Heavily. There's another file, but it's encrypted.
一会儿见
I'll see you in a moment.
探员
Agent.
你查看了我的电脑
You were on my computer.
我是伯利根探员  来自华盛顿部门
Agent Berrigan, D.C. Office.
我有搜查令许可调查此次指导会
I have a warrant for my investigation on mentor.
首都何来功夫操心我的行动
Why is D.C. Looking at my operation?
职责办擅自挪用资源
OPR appropriating resources
针对艺术品盗贼尼尔·卡夫瑞  迹象可疑
for Neal Caffrey, an art thief, raises questions.
这完全合法
It's all legitimate.
我知道
I know.
你还有什么发现
And what else did you find?
加密文件
Encrypted file.
我打不开
I couldn't open it.
我劝你还是还给我吧
I'd like it back.
博尔克
Burke.
福勒  你到底在干什么
Fowler. What the hell are you doing?
我就知道是你
Of course you're involved in this.
站那儿别动
Stay where you are.
放下武器
Lower your weapon.
你根本不知道自己犯了什么错
You have no idea what you're getting into.
-放下武器  -站那儿别动
- Lower your weapon.  - Hey, just stay where you are.
你这是何必
Why are you doing this?
-我们都是自己人  -站住别动
- We're on the same team.  - Stay where you are.
别动  你被卷了进来
Stay where you are. You're in way over your head here.
你完全不知道这有多棘手
You have no idea what you're getting involved in.
你不会对一名探员开枪的
You don't want to shoot an agent.
慢慢放下枪
Now put your gun down. Drop the weapon.
-放下枪  -你才放下枪
- Put your gun down!  - Drop the weapon!
-放下枪  -快放下
- Put the gun down now!  - Drop the weapon! Drop it!
吸气吸气  福勒
Breathe, breathe. Breathe, Fowler.
-你怎么知道他穿防弹衣  -其实我不知道
- How'd you know he was wearing a vest?  - I didn't.
指导会到底是怎么回事
What the hell is mentor?
指导会是合法的  博尔克
Mentor is legit, Burke.
卡夫瑞是我们的人了
Caffrey works for us now.
他和凯特是职责办的深层卧底
He and Kate are deep undercover for OPR.
职责办才没有这种人
OPR doesn't have deep-cover agents.
你是在帮他销声匿迹
You are helping him disappear.
他自己想走
He wants to go.
你又和他见过面了
You met with him again.
尼尔要走了  告诉我他在哪儿
Neal is gonna disappear. I need to know where he is.
快告诉我
Tell me where he is.
你干嘛这么在乎他
Why do you care?
把硬盘给我
Give me the drive.
你到底说不说
You want me to upload this to D.C.,
别逼我把这些上传给首都那边的人看
or do we have something to talk about?
他在哈德逊小机场  4号机库
Airstrip by the Hudson, hangar four.
尼尔
Neal.
你是来逮捕我吗
Are you here to arrest me?
我还是平民一个
I'm still a civilian.
我知道了指导会的事
And I know about mentor.
也知道你可以就这么一走了之  完全合法
And I know you can walk away, and it's all legal.
那你来干什么
Then what are you doing here?
因为我是你的挚友
I'm here as your friend.
你也知道  不管怎样  我都会上飞机
You understand I'm getting on that plane.
这也是你人生中最大的错误
I also know you're making the biggest mistake of your life.
这是最好的结局  彼得
This is what's best for everyone, Peter.
你我彼此间
You go back to your life.
都各自回到原本的生活
I get to have one of my own.
难道这里没有你的生活吗
You already have one right here.
这里有人关心你在乎你
You have people who care about you.
你的出现  使一切都改变了
You make a difference.
真的
You do.
谢谢你给我这个
Thank you for this.
我得走了
I got to go.
唯独对我  你没有说再见
You said goodbye to everyone but me.
为什么
Why?
-我不知道  -你知道  告诉我
- I don't know.  - Yeah, you do. Tell me.
-我不知道  彼得  -为什么
- I don't know, Peter.  - Why?
-你心里知道  -我要你亲口说
- You know why.  - Tell me.
因为自始至终  我只在乎你的感受
'cause you're the only one who could change my mind.
你这么在乎我吗
Did I?
猫咪和耗子都是傻瓜
拼命守护自己爱的人和周围的一切
我们无法安排他们未来的路
只能祈祷这一切都是美好的
因为傻瓜都一样  都会执着在对方身旁
感谢一直以来支持人人猫鼠游戏组的小傻瓜们
我们第二季的时候  不见不散
彼得
Peter.
不
No, no, no, no! No! No!
-不  -别过去
- No! - Stay here.
-不  -快退后
- No! No!  - Stay back!